Andrew Yaros

Data Center Solution Architect at SHI International Corp.

Summary

Solution Architect with extensive experience supporting hardware and software with an emphasis on Enterprise Level Architecture and EUC Solutions. Strengths include pre-sales Technical Support, Evaluation, Planning, Configuration, and Design. Technically adept with a variety of hardware platforms such as DELL, HP, EMC, NetApp, Cisco UCS, Cisco Networking and Storage Connectivity, NAS, SAN, LAN, Disaster Recovery, Data Replication, Data Migration, and Data Center Infrastructure.

Supporting the sales teams in Architecting Solutions using Assessments, System Sizing, Competitive Research, Scoping LOE, Quote/BOM Generation in configuring Servers, SANS, LANS, Storage, Storage Connectivity, Networking, EUC/Visualization, Disaster Recovery, Data Migration, Data Replication, and Data Center Infrastructure.

Passion for customer satisfaction in all aspects of sales and support, striving to build long-term customer relationships. Excellent presentation and facilitation skills working with diverse technical audiences.

Specialties: architecture, cisco, competitive analysis, computer hardware, customer relations, customer satisfaction, data migration, dell computers, disaster recovery planning, hewlett packard, lan, linux, marketing, meeting facilitation, microsoft office, novell, presentation skills, problem solving, prototyping, rfp, sales, sales training, san, seminars, servers, software development, teaching, technical sales, unix, unixware, upgrades,nexus, mds, iscsi, sow, euc

Experience

Data Center Solution Architect at SHI International Corp.

March 2015 - Present

- Architect and Design Server and Storage Solutions with supporting technologies while maintaining customer's budget and environment restrictions
- Assist SHI Sales Reps with customer facing conference calls & presentations
- Deliver related IT assessments to analyze customer environment
- Work with a sales team to identify, gather requirements for solutions, and draft proposals
- Design solutions and plan implementations with the sales team and customer
- Translate business needs into technology specifications
- Assist SHI Sales Reps with the Deal Registration Process

- Provide technical mentoring and development to other team members
- Perform technical presentations, Scope(s) of Work, Bill(s) of Material for customers, partners and prospects.
- Assist with the development of formal sales plans and proposals for assigned opportunities.
- Analyze needs of the Sales team and create supporting documentation or tools to better equip the team in the sales process
- Identify and promote SHI Professional Services
- Work with other SHI pre-sales Solution Architects to expand product sales into solution sales

Data Center Solution Architect at SHI International Corp.

2014 - 2016 (3 years)

Data Center Architect at Pomeroy

June 2013 - November 2014 (1 year 6 months)

- Plan, Design, Configure, and Quote Enterprise Data Center Solutions utilizing DELL, EMC, HP, Cisco, VMware, NetApp and others for Servers, Storage, EUC /Virtualization, Disaster Recovery, Data Migration, Data Replication and Data Center Infrastructure all around EUC, Networking and Data Center.
- Supporting Account Managers in On-site Meetings, Assessments, Competitive Awareness, Solution Design, and Configuration and Quote Generation, as well as Managed Services and Staffing
- Duties include generating RFP Responses, Onsite visits and Presentations, VISIO Diagrams, LOE Scope, Quote and Statement of Work generation encompassing Planning, Designing, Implementation, and Operational phases for Managed and Professional Services.

Data Center Solution Architect at Presidio

October 2011 - March 2013 (1 year 6 months)

- Enterprise Data Center Solutions utilizing EMC, HP, VCE, Cisco, VMware, NetApp and others for Servers, Storage, Virtualization, Disaster Recovery, Data Migration, Data Replication and Data Center Infrastructure.Duties included Planning, Designing, Configuring, and Quote Generation
- Account Manager Support in On-site Meetings, Product Briefings, Competitive Awareness,
 Solution Design, and Configuration and Quote Generation.
- Duties include generating Diagrams, Scope, Pricing and Statement of Work encompassing Planning, Designing, Implementation, and Professional Services

Sr Systems Engineer at Fujitsu

January 2010 - September 2011 (1 year 9 months)

Pre-Sales Server Systems Engineer providing enterprise-level pre-sales support in the development of sales opportunities, together with bringing successful business solutions to customers.

- Design, Configure and Quote enterprise solutions encompassing. Servers, Storage, SAN, LAN, and WAN, surrounding Storage Connectivity, Virtualization, Disaster Recovery, Data Migration and Data Center Infrastructure for Regional and National Sales teams.
- Support Sales Specialists in Product and Road-Map Presentations, RFP responses, Seminars, Trade-Shows, Webinars and all Pre-sales activities.
- Facilitate onsite training to Resellers on Fujitsu's product line and new product releases in the Eastern and Central regions

Sr. Solution Architect

January 2007 - March 2010 (3 years 3 months)

- Pre-sales solution architect for working with six Sales Specialists in the Mid-Atlantic Region.
- Responsible for presales configuration and design of Enterprise solutions encompassing Servers,
 Storage, SANs, LANs, Networking, Virtualization, Diaster Recovery, Data Migration, and Data
 Center Infrastructure.
- Supporting Sale Specialist in Presentations, RFP responses, Seminars, Trade-Shows, and Presales activities

Technical Consultant

January 2003 - May 2006 (3 years 5 months)

- Managed new and existing Customer base for architecting solutions from both a sales and technical perspective in the Mid-Atlantic Region.
- Managed sales cycles and problem resolution for HP, DELL and Z-Corp product lines.
- Lead Technical person for Z-Corp for trade shows, seminars, presentations, and learning sessions.

Solution Architect at Hewlett-Packard

January 1996 - January 2003 (7 years 1 month)

One of the world's leaders in computer manufacturing.

- Supported five sales specialists in solution identification, system sizing, competitive research and configuration generation for sales calls. Managed customer satisfaction in sales cycles.
- Accountable for BETA programs to all new customers. Supported new product launches by delivering technical presentations at customer seminars, tradeshows, and training.
- Maintained technical proficiency in hardware and operating systems to better assist sales specialist in sales cycle. Managed problem resolutions to customer issues for total customer satisfaction.
- Received CEO Customer Satisfaction Award based on quick resolution to major issue with key account.
- Received four Individual Contributor Awards based on exceeding performance standards and achieving high customer satisfaction.
- Selected by Management to support HP's Visualization Product.

- Created and implemented national virtual sales training programs of new products to ensure increased knowledge base to improve sales cycles.
- Managed individual customer sites for the evaluation and beta installation of new products.
- Worked with many major accounts in the Mid-Atlantic Region including AT&T, Bear Sterns, NY Transit, Lockheed Martin, Dresser Rand, Kodak, Ingersol Rand, Telcordia, Hoffman La Roche, T-Mobile, Cordis, AOL, General

Product Manager/TechnicalMarketing Manager at Novell January 1994 - January 1996 (2 years 1 month)

Software and services company specializing in enterprise software systems.

- Managed UnixWare quarterly updates including software development kit, maintenance releases, updates and upgrade releases. Identified and selected enhancements and patches for updated releases.
- Implemented fulfillment process of UnixWare and add-on products.
- Received Novell's Service Excellence Award based on time to market for guarterly releases.
- Trained three field offices and a new fulfillment center to ensure adherence to new procedures.
- As Technical Marketing Manager of Unix System Laboratories, directed all customer briefing activities with one branch office and central briefing center.
- Managed Technology Briefing Center with latest hardware/software for customer showcase.
- Served as lead Technical Advisor for all UNIX related trade shows.
- Facilitated sales training to field offices teaching new product releases.

Education

Pfeiffer University

Andrew Yaros

Data Center Solution Architect at SHI International Corp.



Contact Andrew on LinkedIn